A Guide to the Tazewell family papers, 1623-1930
Library of Virginia
- 8 December 1825 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Littleton T. Waller of Norfolk to Littleton Waller Tazewell-apologizes for not stopping for paper yet, will do so now if not inconvenient-will avail himself of Tazewell's generous offer to let him use the library-will probably do so at the beginning of the week
- 9 December 1825 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  William Wirt at Annapolis to Littleton Waller Tazewell-letter of recommendation for Alexander Scott for an office filled by the Senate
- 10 December 1825 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  John Wickham of Richmond to Littleton Waller Tazewell in Norfolk-regarding Tazewell's health-Tazewell had put off heading to Washington-Randolph elected to Senate
- 10 December 1825 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  George Loyall in Richmond to Littleton Waller Tazewell at Norfolk-sorry to hear of Tazewell's indisposition-John Randolph elected to the Senate-Tyler elected governor-dismay over the president's message
- 28 December 1825 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  John Wickham of Richmond to Littleton Waller Tazewell in Washington-regarding Tazewell's health-Tazewell in the Senate-the Convention question
- 1826 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  receipt from Mutual Assurance Society to Sarah Nivison for payment on buildings in Norfolk-policy 3851
- 14 [15] February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Hugh Lawson White to Littleton Waller Tazewell-Senate has done nothing yet on Panama Mission
- 1826 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  receipt from Mutual Assurance Society to Sarah Nivison and Louisa G. Nivison (Coles) for payment on buildings in Norfolk-policy 3852
- 17-18 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  John Randolph of Roanoke to Littleton Waller Tazewell-president's answer to Van Buren's resolutions-everyone glad to hear of Tazewell's good news-thinks White is almost as attached to Tazewell as is Randolph
- 15-16 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  John Randolph to Littleton Waller Tazewell-Van Buren's resolutions on Panama Mission pass 23-19-his letter of a couple days previous
- 8 January 1826 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Robert Archer at Fortress Monroe to Littleton Waller Tazewell-regarding the military medical staff, specifically pay
- 9 January 1826 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  George Hay of Loudoun County to Littleton Waller Tazewell-Hay had asked the Secretary of the Treasury to bring suit against him (Hay-judge of the eastern district of the United States)-nothing can be done until gets back to Washington-Hay's published response to Giles-believes that Giles' attacks not aimed at him but at James Monroe-Giles implied that Hay using his position to supply funds to Monroe who was broke-Giles a small man in Hay's estimation
- 17 January 1826 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Alexander Scott of Georgetown to Littleton Waller Tazewell-forwarding a letter from Bushrod Washington to William Wirt concerning Scott-see letter above 9 December 1825
- 17 January 1825 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  17 January 1825 [notation on back of letter states 1826]-Ludwell Lee to Littleton Waller Tazewell-letter of recommendation for Richard Lowe as office of registrar of East Florida
- 20 January 1826 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  cover for a letter from John B. Neilson to Littleton Waller Tazewell-letter is not with it
- 20 January 1826 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  George Hay in Georgetown to Littleton Waller Tazewell-has found book which contains the money belonging to U.S. received by him-also son and assistant are going through receipts and papers-will, if Tazewell doesn't mind, pass the finished product to him-Hay wants vindication-Hay letters seem to deal with his appointment to a position on the federal bench
- 27 January 1826 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  John Wickham in Richmond to Littleton Waller Tazewell-concerning Tazewell's health-convention bill negatived yesterday-future of efforts?-efforts to amend U.S. Constitution
- 30 January 1826 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  George Hay in Georgetown to Littleton Waller Tazewell-again his case before the senate-see above letters from Hay
- 5 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Benjamin Watkins Leigh of Richmond to Littleton Waller Tazewell-Benton's report on election of the president-Leigh's comments regarding it-had convention bill passed house would've passed senate
- 6 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  George Hay in Georgetown to Littleton Waller Tazewell-again his accounts before the house judiciary committee-see above George Hay letters
- 8 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  George Hay to Littleton Waller Tazewell-a list of Hay's writings-willing to pay account if forgot one-enclosure of his writings
- 8 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  William F. Wickham of Richmond to Littleton Waller Tazewell-Baldwin has $3000 to pay part of debt-Wickham is instituting a suit for rest-another debt Wickham is trying to collect that Tazewell was involved in-reconsideration of convention question lost-bill for Jefferson to hold a lottery will be considered and probably will not pass-regrets that great men of nation must "bring wants before the nation-will be amended
- 8 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  William Gaston of Raleigh NC to Littleton Waller Tazewell-detained in Raleigh by Supreme Court matters and unable to attend steamboat company meeting-Mr. Meredith wants an authenticated copy of the act by which company was formed-sending it to Tazewell to pass along
- 9 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  George Hay to Littleton Waller Tazewell-again his list of writings-also asks that committee dispose of his subject as soon as possible
- 11 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell to John Randolph-Tazewell must return home, his wife is deathly ill-doesn't know if he'll come back-regrets not being able to see Randolph before he goes
- 12 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  John Randolph to Littleton Waller Tazewell-was out riding when received news from Hamilton of SC about Tazewell's wife-went to Tazewell's but missed him-met with Hugh Lawson White-found Tazewell's note upon his arrival home-pleads with Tazewell not to resign seat until they can talk-Tazewell and Randolph can work well together-Barbour would've thwarted the good that Tazewell is trying to do-trust in God-talked to Van Buren and Berrian-will try to postpone the Panama Mission 'till Tazewell returns-again a plea not to resign-worst thing to happen to Virginia since Washington's death if does-if Tazewell goes, Randolph will also go
- 12 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell to John Randolph-sending Randolph his papers on the Panama Mission-apologies but states he's writing and sending these papers to occupy his mind while he waits for a stage-asks Randolph to write often to give him news-will be governed by Randolph's information-if wife has recovered enough, will return-if not, he won't return-will consult with friends in Richmond to determine whether he should resign so that Virginia has two senators on site rather than one
- 13 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  John Randolph to Littleton Waller Tazewell-brief note saying he'd written a long letter and sent it to Norfolk-asks Tazewell to do nothing until he reads the letter
- 14 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  John Wickham of Richmond to Littleton Waller Tazewell-latest news is that Tazewell's wife is better but still suffering-information on the mails
- 14 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  John Randolph to Littleton Waller Tazewell-comments on Tazewell's trip-wishes had been able to see him before he left-again begs Tazewell not to resign-is too talented to be wasted-needed by "poor old mother Virginia"-more on the Panama Mission
- 15 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Hugh Lawson White to Littleton Waller Tazewell-bill regarding the Florida Canal-reported with amendment to build one from Mississippi River to Appalachicola River-also Van Buren's resolutions on the Panama Mission pass 23-19
- 15 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  John Randolph to Littleton Waller Tazewell-has forwarrded his papers-thinks Tazewell can make it back by the vote on Panama, provided that Mrs. Tazewell is fine-again pleads with Tazewell not to resign-could work with any of the other folks the Virginia assembly might send-knew only 4 of 24 Virginia Senators and 14 of 216 delegates
- 16 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell in Norfolk to John Randolph-arrived home-description of wife's health and treatments (drew 72 ounces of blood)-has done nothing about his position and won't do anything until has talked to Randolph-they are close friends-death of his slave John
- 17 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell to John Randolph-news of his wife's health-his own health-Randolph to decide their course-Tazewell thought his resignation would have been best for Randolph and Virginia-both deserve full attention and support-probably won't be back for some weeks unless the date of the vote is known fairly in advance
- 17 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Hugh Lawson White to Littleton Waller Tazewell-have president's answer to Van Buren's resolutions-he gives no consent to open doors-question of publishing for the Senates the resolutions and the president's answer being debated-decided in the affirmative
- 17 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Hugh Lawson White to Littleton Waller Tazewell-vote on nomination of purser Robert Pottinger [?] Senate tied 20-20-broken for confirmation by president of the Senate
- 17 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  John Randolph to Littleton Waller Tazewell-minor vote on naval officer-heard that Tazewell must have received his letter sent via Brockenbrough-news about Giles-has heard from Wickham about Mrs. Tazewell-is glad
- 19 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  John Randolph to Littleton Waller Tazewell-Pennsylvania Senators voted against report-including Tazewell, 5 Senators out who supported report
- 20 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  certificate by Alexander Tunstall collector of the Norfolk District that George Hay paid $1552.17 on the duty bonds of Thomas Willock May 1814
- 20 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell to George Hay-has forwarded their correspondence to Col. [Robert Y.] Hayne-believes that Hay will be confirmed for his position on the bench-see above Hay letters
- 20 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell to John Randolph-brief letter saying he is very sick and his wife is a bit better
- 20 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Hugh Lawson White to Littleton Waller Tazewell-Mrs. Tazewell's health-received answer from the president regarding Van Buren's resolutions-Senate creating a committee-points it will address-confidential publication of papers
- 20 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  John Randolph to Littleton Waller Tazewell-mentions his own slave John-Mrs. Tazewell's health-Tazewell's remarks on a Randolph speech
- 21 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell to Robert Y. Hayne-sending Hay's correspondence-health is bad
- 21 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  John Randolph to Littleton Waller Tazewell-after consulting the vice president, is sending president's answer and Van Buren's resolutions to Tazewell-speech of Rowan of KY answered by Holmes of ME-more discussion on Panama Mission and other items-postscript on the VA resolutions of 1798-1799-slam on the VA presidents
- 22 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  John Randolph to Littleton Waller Tazewell-goings-on in the Senate-still part of the Panama Mission
- 22 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell to John Randolph-his health, appreciates Randolph's letters-asks him to keep writing
- 23 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell to John Randolph-again his health-had opposed delay to the "measure alluded to"-forwarding a letter
- 23 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Hugh Lawson White to Littleton Waller Tazewell-proceedings in the Senate-Resolutions arising out of the Panama Mission-the vote
- 23 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  John Randolph to Littleton Waller Tazewell-action in the Senate, mainly concerning the Panama Mission
- 24 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Hugh Lawson White to Littleton Waller Tazewell-Senate proceedings, Panama Mission
- 24 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  John Randolph to Littleton Waller Tazewell-Senate proceedings, mainly Panama Mission
- 25 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  John Randolph to Littleton Waller Tazewell-some politics-says that he and Tazewell will see each other again in this world
- 25 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  George Hay of Georgetown to Littleton Waller Tazewell-concerning his financial concerns and his appointment-see above George Hay letters
- 25 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Hugh Lawson White to Littleton Waller Tazewell-Panama Mission
- 25 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell to John Randolph-his health
- 26 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  John Randolph to Littleton Waller Tazewell-brief note
- 27 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  John Randolph to Littleton Waller Tazewell-Randolph's health-too much letter writing-turning down Mr. Newsum's request-death of Gaillard of SC-went to see White, but White was at church-gossip on political figures
- 27 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell to John Randolph-health still bad-doesn't know when or if he'll return to the Senate-has written Loyall and stated that if VA legislature thinks it best under circumstances, Tazewell will resign-will be governed by Loyall's answer
- 28 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell (written by John N. Tazewell) to John Randolph-news of him and family sent up in a letter to White-argues for the minority in Senate to follow a moral course and be patient under all abuse-will win in end
- 28 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  John Randolph to Littleton Waller Tazewell-returning Newsum's letter-Gaillard's funeral
- 28 February 1826 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  John Randolph to Littleton Waller Tazewell-John C. Calhoun-reminiscences of schools days-buried Gaillard of SC
- 1 March 1826 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  John Randolph to Littleton Waller Tazewell-note-general comments-showed letters to White
- 1 March 1826 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Hugh Lawson White to Littleton Waller Tazewell-glad to hear that Tazewell's wife is better-discussion of bearing the woes of this world-Gailllard's death-Panama Mission-death of White's son
- 2 March 1826 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  John N. Tazewell to John Randolph-writing for his father-his parents' health-Tazewell regrets forwarding Newsum's letter containing his proposal-barely knows Newsum-Tazewell says Randolph must write only at his convenience, and appreciates the letters sent-asks about the bankrupt bill-Tazewell is against the bankrupt bill-U.S. can't bear a bankrupt system
- 4 March 1826 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell to John Randolph-his health, his wife's health-comments on Gaillard's death-Calhoun
- 5 March 1826 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  John Randolph to Littleton Waller Tazewell-hasn't received a letter from Tazewell in a while-concerned and unhappy-regarding Tazewell's comment about resigning-Virginia is too proud of him to let him go-comments on the Senate-changed lodgings
- 5 March 1826 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  B. W. Johnston of Port Gibson MS to Littleton Waller Tazewell-asks for help in being appointed postmaster at Natchez
- 6 March 1826 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell to John Randolph-health and weather
- 7 March 1826 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  John Randolph to John N. Tazewell-thanks him for letter- high praise for Tazewell, his oldest friend
- 7 March 1826 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  John Randolph to Littleton Waller Tazewell-received John's letter and one from Tazewell in same packet-well overjoyed-more on Senate and Panama Mission
- 7 March 1826 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  John Randolph to Littleton Waller Tazewell-Randolph's health
- 8 March 1826 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  John Randolph to Littleton Waller Tazewell-cover of letter from Randolph-letter not with it
- 9 March 1826 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell to John Randolph-health of wife-birth of daughter-doesn't care about bashers that Randolph mentioned (doesn't know who he means)-true to self and to Virginia-received answer from Loyall who consulted others in Richmond-they don't think he should resign, but should stay with his family until all are well
- 10 March 1826 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Hugh Lawson White to Littleton Waller Tazewell-debate on the Panama Mission-able speeches by Van Buren, Randolph-son's death
- 13 March 1826 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  John Randolph to Littleton Waller Tazewell-Panama mission-those who spoke against Tazewell-Randolph's dinner guests (Marshall, Calhoun, Van Buren, Sanford, Hayne, Hamilton, Woodbury, Williams)-why he left his former lodgings
- 13 March 1826 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell to John Randolph-wife's health-way of the most high is mysterious-should not question
- 14 March 1826 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Hugh Lawson White to Littleton Waller Tazewell-will be voting on Panama Mission soon-probably will be 24-19 for
- 14 March 1826 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  John Randolph to Littleton Waller Tazewell-asks if he has copy of Randolph's motion withdrawn to make room for Woodbury's
- 18 March 1826 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Hugh Lawson White to Littleton Waller Tazewell-president sent documents for Panama Mission-house ordered printing 10,000 copies-secrecy could be lifted-regrets that Mrs. Tazewell still unwell-trials that all suffer-death of his son
- 21 March 1826 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  John Randolph to Littleton Waller Tazewell-troubles writing
- 25 March 1826 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  George Hay of Georgetown to Senator Robert Y. Hayne of SC-regarding papers concerning Hay that Tazewell sent to him
- 29 March 1826 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  William Smith at Old Plantation in Northampton County to Littleton Waller Tazewell-Aaron has died-has begun planting corn-ploughs
- 30 March 1826 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  George Hay to Littleton Waller Tazewell-glad that Tazewell is back in his Senate seat
- 1 April 1826 (Box 5, Folder 7 (Begin Misc. reel #674))
  Theodore Stark of Mississippi but in Washington to Littleton Waller Tazewell-asks for his opinion of Mather and Mather vs. Stark and others
- 1 April 1826 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  John Cowper of Norfolk to Littleton Waller Tazewell at Washington-asks him, despite his feelings, to have bill for Dismal Swamp Canal brought forward-Mrs. Tazewell getting better
- 2 April 1826 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  George Hay of Washington (Georgetown) to Littleton Waller Tazewell--received Tazewell's note yesterday morning--will respond to it when he gets home in a day--asks Tazewell to return papers
- 3 April 1826 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  John Wickham of Richmond to Littleton Waller Tazewell-glad that Tazewell is back in Senate-received documents on the Panama Mission-agrees with Report and Tazewell-proposed changes in the Constitution (U.S.)
- 6 April 1826 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Robert Goode of Norfolk County to Littleton Waller Tazewell in Washington-understands that two new companies of cavalry are being raised-asks for Tazewell's support of his application as major of one
- 8 April 1826 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  J. Meredith of Baltimore MD to Littleton Waller Tazewell [?]-copy of letter-reached a settlement for Newbern Steam Boat company against Ferguson
- 12 April 1826 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  William S. Smith at Old Plantation to Littleton Waller Tazewell-planting and work at Old Plantation in Northampton County-note on back notes that letter delivered 17 April
- 14 April 1826 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Richard Gatewood of Norfolk to Littleton Waller Tazewell-articles in the Norfolk Herald (pro-Adams)-Taylor's [?] election to House of Delegates-Loyall's election secure
- 17 April 1826 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  George Hay at Loudoun County to Littleton Waller Tazewell-appreciates all that Tazewell has done for him
- 17 April 1826 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Richard Gatewood of Norfolk to Littleton Waller Tazewell-election of Taylor to the House of Delegates from Norfolk County
- 21 April 1826 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  William Gaston of Newbern NC to Littleton Waller Tazewell-sending copy of letter from J. Meredith regarding settlement (see 8 April letter-conservation)
- 22 April 1826 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  John Randolph to Littleton Waller Tazewell-is unwell and will not be in the Senate today
- 23 April 1826 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  John Wickham of Richmond to Littleton Waller Tazewell-Tazewell's health-Mrs. Wickham's health-results of elections throughout state might add to conventionist strength-proposed change in U.S. constitution for election of president-John Randolph
- 25 April 1826 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Richard Gatewood to Littleton Waller Tazewell-election results in Norfolk-Loyall elected 218 to 215
- 29 April 1826 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  William S. Smith at Old Plantation to Littleton Waller Tazewell-Old Plantation news--note from John N. Tazewell concerning sale of wheat--no one knows where Henry is
- 8 May 1826 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  John Cowper of Norfolk to Littleton Waller Tazewell-wondering if he needs to go to Washington
- 10 May 1826 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  William S. Smith at Old Plantation to Littleton Waller Tazewell-Old Plantation news
- 15 May 1826 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Robert Saunders of Williamsburg to Littleton Waller Tazewell-Saunders' son travelling to France for his health-Saunders asks Tazewell to send papers for passport plus a declaration by French ambassador to his son in New York
- 22 May 1826 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Gabriel Galt of Portsmouth to Littleton Waller Tazewell-asking about his nephew's application to West Point
- 26 May 1826 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  James Hoshor of the Philomathean Society of Ohio University in Athens Ohio to Littleton Waller Tazewell-stating that Tazewell has been elected a member of the society
- 27 May 1826 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  William Gaston of Newbern NC to Littleton Waller Tazewell-resolutions of the Newbern Steam Boat Company concerning the settlement that J. Meredith reached against Ferguson
- 29 May 1826 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell invoice with Benj. Ferguson via Walton and Gray
- 30 May 1826 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- 31 May 1826 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Robert Saunders of Williamsburg to Littleton Waller Tazewell-Saunders' son travelling to France for his health-letter not gotten in time-appreciates Tazewell's willingness to still help-asks that he forward it to French Minister then have minister send documentation to Dr. Robert Greenhow of NY who will forward it on to Saunders' son
- 31 May 1826 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  W. McIlvaine, cashier of the Bank of the United States to Littleton Waller Tazewell-received Tazewell's checks which will go toward purchasing stock
- 3 June 1826 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Samuel Frothingham cashier Bank of the United States, Boston branch, to Littleton Waller Tazewell-as per Tazewell's request has taken stock off their books and sent a certificate of transfer to Washington cashier-has received Tazewell's check
- 3 June 1826 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  John Wickham of Richmond to Littleton Waller Tazewell of Norfolk-hopes Tazewell is in good health-comments on the U.S. constitution-interpretations of that document-asks Tazewell what he will be doing this summer-a p.s. on Mrs. Tazewell's health-Wickham's wife's health-other family and personal items
- 8 June 1826 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Thomas M. Bayly of the Eastern Shore, but writing from Norfolk to Governor John Tyler-Judge George Parker resigning his commission as judge of the general court-Eastern Shore folks-recommends Tazewell as successor after Tazewell stated he would not seek the office but would accept it if offered to him
- 12 June 1826 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Smith B. Nottingham of Northampton County to Littleton Waller Tazewell-would like to close a bill of sale on a schooner owned by Capt. William Hall and has a claim by Tazewell
- 12 June 1826 (Box 5, Folder 8)